[mysterious music]
- [thunder rumbling]
- [rain pattering]
[banging on door]
[Owen breathing heavily]
- [Owen coughs]
- [banging on door continues]
[Neil] Please.
I need to see her.
I'm going to tell you what I tell
everyone who comes through that door,
looking to see her.
Leave.
Take your grief elsewhere.
- You'll find no peace here.
- No, I'm not looking for peace.
- I'm looking for answers.
- Go home.
Go home!
[♪]
This property comes
with a special tenant.
Lives in the basement.
She's tied to the property.
And now that your name
is on the title deeds,
you're her guardian.
You can't escape this place now.
[timer ticking]
You're the one thing that stands
between her and the outside world,
and that now is your sole task.
You cannot...
let her...
out of the basement.
You don't know yet
how dangerous she is.
But she is, and you will.
[♪]
But tonight, her curse ends with me.
If you're watching this,
then I failed--
[light bulb shatters]
- [Owen sniffles, grunts]
- [lighter clicking]
[Owen panting]
[shriek]
But you should know...
[Owen screams]
...you're already dead.
- [snarling]
- [Owen screaming]
[Owen groaning, panting]
[Owen shouting]
[ominous music]
[solemn music]
[window rattling]
- [Iris] I've almost got it.
- [rattling continues]
There.
[grunting]
You know, it's illegal
to break into an apartment
- once you've been evicted from it.
- Yeah, Katie, I know.
It's shit, but he's done it anyway.
Probably knows I can't afford
to do anything about it.
Sorry about this.
Look, you know I'm supposed to
hear about that art scholarship soon.
- Okay.
- I just got to sort things,
you know, for the deposit and stuff.
Do you reckon Martin would
give me my shift back at the hotel?
- That job was rubbish.
- Well, yeah,
- but I don't really care about--
- Martin's a pervert.
True.
Hey.
However long you need, I got you.
- [phone ringing]
- We'll figure it out.
Hello? Yeah,
I'm really sorry, but I'm--
Yeah.
Where?
Yeah. Yeah, I'll-- I can get there.
Okay.
What is it?
Um, my dad.
You said your dad was dead.
Yep. Well, he is now.
[eerie music]
[hoarse, indistinct whisper]
[♪]
[officer] I'm very sorry, Miss Lark.
You're the only next of kin.
Is this your father?
[Owen screams]
[♪]
Iris Lark.
My-- my condolences.
I'm the solicitor acting on behalf
of your father's estate.
I can review his assets with you once
we have, uh, liquidated the property.
Sorry, what property?
My dad owned this place?
[solicitor] Yes. Well, not exactly
a modern-day discotheque.
But, fortunately,
that need be no concern of yours.
Once you sign over permission
for me to act as executor,
well, I can handle the sale
and the transition of ownership.
Do you mind if we look inside?
[door creaking]
[solicitor] In you go. Here we are.
Numerous owners
have made various attempts
to reinvent this place
over the past 400 years.
And your father was so deep in debt
that selling the pub for a profit
would be a financial impossibility,
I'm afraid.
And a full restoration would require
a significant financial investment.
Fortunately,
I work with a consortium of investors
who have a vast experience
in offloading
these type of derelict buildings.
[sinister music]
[♪]
[music intensifies]
Truly a dreadful affair.
What's up there?
[solicitor] Hmm.
Hmm.
Was he leaving?
Uh, I have no record of any attempt
to put the property on the market.
We should be able to finalise
the details this afternoon,
if you'd care to.
I just wanna talk with my lawyer.
Historic properties, you know,
they can be irksome in their nuance.
- You know, the ex--
- Oh, no, no, she's-- she's great.
Hey, is it all right
if I crash here tonight?
- [Katie on phone] What's it like?
- [Iris] A bit creepy, to be honest.
- How are you?
- Fine.
- Iris...
- Yeah, I don't know.
I just can't stop picturing him.
His-- his body.
Don't think about that.
Try to think of a good memory
you have with him.
[scoffs] I don't have
good memories with him.
I don't have any memories with him.
Iris, I should be there with you.
I'm coming.
No, don't worry.
You've already paid for my flight.
I'm fine, okay?
No, I-- I'm coming.
I've already bought a ticket.
[chuckles] Of course you did.
Iris...
don't do anything until I get there.
Okay?
Well, see you soon, then.
Yeah. See you soon.
Bye.
[low, eerie music]
[soft, steady ticking]
[wind whistling faintly]
[soft sigh]
[faint, indistinct whispers]
[whispers continue]
[timer ringing]
No.
Hello?
[♪]
[Iris breathing shakily]
[faint, hoarse whispers]
[♪]
[breathing shakily]
- No.
- Shit!
No, wait. It's all right.
Keep away from me!
Stay the hell away from me!
[softly] I didn't mean to scare you.
You're the new owner?
My name's Neil.
Yeah?
What do you want?
I want to see her.
I-- I'm sorry.
I-- I know I-- I should've waited.
I should've given you more time.
- I--
- Please, you don't understand. I...
- I don't know. I don't--
- I need to see her.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
It's 2,000.
Right?
What-- what e--
what exactly is this for?
The woman in the basement.
Look, please.
I need to see my wife.
I'm really sorry, your wife is not
here. There's no one else here.
Yes, she is.
She's downstairs.
Is-- is this some kind of joke?
Are you--
Is this some kind of sick joke
or something?
- Or--
- It's not. No.
Look, how much do you need? I, uh...
4,000?
Please?
I can bring the rest tomorrow.
Look, I-- I promise
I'm not crazy, okay?
Other people come here
for the same reason.
Look...
why don't you just--
just take the money?
I know what to do.
I don't have a key right now.
Why-- why don't you
come back tomorrow night?
Yeah?
- I'm keeping this.
- All right.
Yes. Tomorrow.
Listen, I can't-- I'm-- Thank you.
Thank you. [sniffles]
And knock next time.
[♪]
[rain pattering]
[solicitor] I must confess,
I'm rather taken aback
by your decision.
It's-- I do hope you
find yourself up to the task.
[pensive music]
[Iris] It's not long.
I just want a little time
in my Dad's old place.
[solicitor] Well, I suppose
these things have a tendency of
unfolding as they do for a reason.
Sometimes the wrong path
leads us to the right place.
[♪]
I'm sure you'll have
more than enough time
to find what you're looking for.
[♪]
The last page.
It's an old building,
with ancient traditions.
[foreboding music]
[♪]
It's in your hands now.
- [Iris] Thanks for everything.
- Oh, one other thing.
Your-- your father, he, um,
anticipated that The Queen's Head
might fall under new management,
so he left, um,
instructions for the new owner.
Um, instructions for what?
Oh, they were not left for me.
They were left for the--
the new owner.
[♪]
[rain pattering]
[car horn honks]
This should be fun.
[Katie] You already signed?
Listen, it's my pub for the time being,
and then I can just...
sell it whenever I bloody want.
[Katie] Okay, but why?
Okay. Listen, Katie.
This is-- It's gonna sound mad.
- You're joking, Iris.
- I know. I know, I know.
But it's-- it's 4,000,
and he's bringing
the other half tonight.
You've invited a stranger,
a potential psychopath?
Just-- Okay, listen to me.
Hear me out.
I bet that there are
tons of people who came here
and paid my dad to just go down there
and have a bit of a scare.
You know? Just... for laughs.
[eerie music]
[cuckoo clock chiming]
- [banging on door]
- [Katie gasps]
That's him.
[♪]
That's it.
[lock clicks]
[♪]
Hello?
If you're in there, come out.
Maybe it's on the toilet.
It does smell like shit down here.
Come out, come out, wherever you are.
Just wait.
Should we hold hands or something?
Okay. We've given it a shot.
- Do you wanna...
- Shh!
...have a look around?
Listen.
[soft growling]
[Katie] What is that?
Iris.
[growling intensifies]
[music intensifies]
Iris.
Let's go.
Iris!
We need your help.
My wife, she died last year.
I need to speak with her.
- What-- No, not her.
- [Katie] Iris, run!
Get away from her!
- Get back!
- Stop.
Don't touch me.
Stay back.
Stay back!
She obeys you.
Of course.
Tell her to sit in the chair.
Price just doubled.
- Anything.
- Iris, no.
- This is mad.
- It's fine.
[breathing heavily] It's obeying me.
Sit in the chair.
[Baghead growling softly]
[♪]
I want to talk to my wife.
Can you do that?
[Baghead growling softly]
Wait, that's my wife's.
- What's happening, Neil?
- [Neil] I don't know.
- What's going on?
- [Neil] I've never done this before.
[Iris] What?
[Baghead snarls]
We need to strap her in the chair.
- Strap her in the chair!
- You strap her in the chair!
[♪]
[Baghead shrieking]
[low growl]
[gasps]
[sobbing]
[Neil] Sarah?
No. No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
No, I can't. I can't. She...
I assure you this isn't necessary.
Can you loosen these?
This isn't right. I can't do this.
I-- I said I needed to speak
to my wife.
We-- we need to start this again.
Charles? Is that you?
Please. Please, I don't--
I need to talk to Sarah, okay?
- [Neil panting]
- Wait.
You're not Charles. You look like...
[scoffs]
[scoffs] It can't be.
You're dead, Mum.
It's been 20 years.
That can't be right.
I'm not-- I don't--
- I don't want to be dead.
- [Neil] Really?
Then why would you do it to yourself?
Do you know I was the one who had
to find you face down in the bathtub?
I would never do that.
You know what?
I didn't want to talk to you,
but here you are.
So maybe you can tell me
why you did it.
You know, I was-- I was passed around
from relatives to boarding schools,
the whole time thinking
it was my fault.
I...
I don't... [sobbing]
[water trickling]
[Katie, whispering] What is that?
[Iris] Neil? Neil!
[dissonant music]
[distorted] The truth is,
I couldn't stand the sight of you.
You ruined my life.
Is that hard to hear, sweet boy?
I never wanted to be a mother.
Every second of every day
was a little death.
And one day,
all those deaths added up.
- Should we stop?
- No.
That's right, no.
Not until I get a kiss.
Isn't that what you came for?
You never wanted to kiss me
when you were little.
But now you've grown.
And you owe your mother a kiss.
[bones cracking]
[all panting]
The chair.
Give me a kiss!
[Katie] Iris!
[grunting, gagging]
- Iris!
- Stop!
Get the bag. Get the bag!
[Neil grunting]
[Baghead shrieks]
[Baghead snarls]
Get back there.
[Baghead growls]
[♪]
[ominous music]
[Baghead growling softly]
[Neil] It was-- it was the ring.
It was the ring.
It was my mother's
before I gave it to Sarah.
That's what must've confused her.
That thing wasn't confused.
It knew what it was doing.
[Neil] Wait, wait, there was a timer.
The old man, he had rules.
It was only supposed to be
two minutes.
- I just-- I forgot.
- You forgot?
It worked. It worked, didn't it?
I mean, I didn't even know
if I believed it myself.
Look, listen to me.
Next time, we won't make mistakes.
- There's no next time.
- She was-- she was right there.
I mean, if it can bring back my
mother, it can bring back Sarah.
[panting]
Your wife is dead.
And you don't get to see her anymore.
It's what we agreed.
If you change your mind...
Look, um, money's really no object.
I just want the chance to say goodbye.
If you're watching this,
then I failed.
I'm leaving you this tape
so you don't make
the same mistakes I've made.
Not that it matters.
You're already dead.
This property comes
with a special tenant.
Lives in the basement.
Now that your name
is on the title deeds,
she's tied to you too.
You're her guardian.
She'll obey you, and only you.
To a point.
There's a hole in the far wall.
She can't harm you
as long as you stay on your side,
so you stay away from the hole.
She has the power
to bring back the dead.
But I warn you. Don't use her.
- You'll be tempted.
- [Baghead shrieks]
Don't use her.
When I became her guardian,
I was weak.
I couldn't help myself.
But here's the thing.
She only gives you two minutes.
Two minutes with the dead.
After that, she's in control.
No chains or straps
will hold her down.
The longer you talk to her,
the stronger she becomes.
She'll crawl inside your head.
Even if you try to leave,
sickness and death will follow you.
Her spells float up
from the basement like ghosts.
One way or another,
she'll bring you back here.
Anything to have you set her free.
That's her one goal.
So, you cannot
let her out of the basement.
Ever.
You're the one thing that stands
between her and the outside world.
It seemed like a blessing once,
having access to her gifts.
But tonight, her curse ends with me.
I had a family once.
I had a daughter.
I had a whole life...
beyond this God-forsaken place.
[Iris breathes shakily]
And now I only have her.
[Iris exhales shakily]
Did you know?
No.
It doesn't make any sense!
Why is there a woman in the basement,
and how long has she been down there?
- I don't know.
- We just need to go.
No.
[Katie] No?
We pay for the tickets,
and then what?
I don't even have a place to live.
Neil's rich.
He said he'll pay whatever.
And now we know that there are rules.
We-- we know what we're dealing with.
- No, we don't.
- Well, we know enough!
Katie, please.
Please just listen to me.
Do-- do you know
what this could mean for me?
For you and me?
Because every time I make a little
ground, there's always something
that knocks me back right
where I started.
When we were in group home,
you were the one who always said,
"One day we'll be on our own.
We'll be making our own choices."
This is for us.
You could-- you could study law,
and I could start my art studio.
- I think we deserve that.
- You heard what your dad said.
The more you use her,
the more control she has.
Well, easy for him to say.
He used the basement for 20 years
before he suddenly decided
to get all careful about it.
- But look what it did to him.
- Just a couple of days.
It's a couple of days.
We can handle a couple of days.
And I'm not my dad.
Just once. Just him.
Yeah, and then-- and then we'll go.
I will stay because I care about you.
But, Iris...
we are not safe here.
It has to obey me.
Right?
[♪]
I'm the owner now.
You can't cross this step.
You cannot leave this basement.
[Iris sighs]
[♪]
[buzzer]
[Neil over intercom] Who is it?
Um, it's Iris, you know,
from the pub.
[Neil] Iris.
I didn't think I'd hear from you.
Come on in. It's open.
[Katie sighs]
- [Katie gasps]
- [glass shattering]
[tense music]
[Katie breathing shakily]
[♪]
[Katie] Otto Vogler.
You were the owner once.
"Local bar owner
takes his own life...
after family tragedy."
Friedland?
[sighs]
[gasps]
[panting]
[piano key dings softly]
[piano lid thuds]
So, after Sarah, I was going to
these, um, grief counselling groups.
We were close with
one of the older guys there.
He'd, um, lost his wife to cancer
and was really struggling to go on.
And then one day, he said
he'd found something incredible.
Beyond comprehension.
He said that you-- uh, you pay 2,000,
and he'd take you down to see her.
You had to bring an item
that belonged to the deceased...
and then you could talk to them.
Place I was in, I would've believed
anything just to see her again.
You know the owner was my dad?
And he never told you?
Well, I mean,
we hadn't spoken in years, so.
I didn't even know where he was.
Don't tell me
you haven't thought about it.
If you could have one
real conversation,
the chance to say to his face
how you really feel...
I wish I could offer you
something more than money.
All I want is the chance to say
goodbye.
[disquieting music]
This was hers.
[♪]
[Baghead shrieking]
[growls]
Two minutes.
[ticking]
[♪]
[Sarah inhales deeply]
[Neil gasps, chuckles]
Sarah.
Where am I? Neil.
Neil, where-- where are we?
- What's going on?
- Sarah.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
- What's the last thing you remember?
- I don't know.
[sniffles] I-- I was driving.
You were driving. And then what?
It was raining.
And-- and all the lights
blurred together, and...
then everything went blank.
[sniffing] Neil, what's going on?
[sobbing]
I'm-- I'm-- I'm really scared.
[Neil] I know.
- [timer ticking]
- Ninety seconds.
- Who's that?
- [Neil] It doesn't matter.
Just look at me.
We don't have much time.
You were in an accident.
You crashed your car.
- You died, Sarah.
- [sobs] I what?
It doesn't matter,
because you're here now.
You're here now. [weeping]
[breathing shakily]
Why am I strapped down, then?
I can't explain that right now, okay?
There's-- there's so much
I wanna tell you.
And I know I wasn't perfect.
There's so much
I wish I'd done better.
But I do need to ask you one thing.
[sniffles] What is it?
Who was it you were seeing?
[ominous music]
Seeing?
Neil, I don't-- I don't--
It's all in the past now.
But it would help me to know.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Thirty seconds.
[Neil] Sarah, please.
I know you were going to leave me.
I know there was someone else.
You left the tickets out
on my laptop.
I think you wanted me to find them.
[Iris] Ten seconds.
So who was it?
[Iris] Neil, five seconds.
[shouting] Look,
I am trying to move on!
I just need to know what happened.
- [timer ringing]
- Iris.
- Iris, the time!
- Wait.
- [Iris] Neil, we're done.
- [thunder booms]
[distorted]
There was no other man, Neil.
I just couldn't stand the thought
of being with you any longer.
That's enough.
Stop!
- [truck horn blaring]
- [brakes squealing]
- [crashing]
- [glass shattering]
[car alarm beeping]
[sirens wailing]
[Sarah sobbing]
[Katie] Iris, get back!
[Sarah] I don't wanna be dead.
[Iris] Sarah?
[Sarah sobbing] I...
- [Katie] Iris!
- [Sarah] It wasn't my fault.
It-- I-- I didn't do anything.
- [Iris] I'm here to help you.
- [Sarah sobs]
- [Sarah] I'm scared.
- [Iris] Let me help you.
- [snarls]
- [Iris shrieks]
[Baghead growling]
[Iris grunts]
[Baghead snarling]
[muffled speech]
- [Iris panting]
-[Katie] Iris!
I am your guardian.
You have to listen to me.
[Baghead] You still don't understand.
We are both prisoners.
[♪]
- [Neil breathing heavily]
- This wasn't about saying goodbye.
Was it?
Wouldn't you want to know?
If someone you loved was gonna leave
you, wouldn't you want to know why?
But what she said at the end there...
That was after the timer
had finished, wasn't it?
That-- that wasn't her.
- That was the--
- Doesn't matter.
You had your chance. Now get out.
You should go home, Neil.
I'm sorry.
[eerie music]
[♪]
[softly] I'm not scared of you.
[music intensifies]
[woman] Owen.
You look old.
I'm sick, Cat.
My whole life has been here.
I've had enough.
So I'm gonna go and see Iris.
Try and explain. [coughs]
I wa-- [coughing]
[timer ringing]
[♪]
I wanted to say goodbye.
And now I've said it, so, um...
Remember what happened
the last time you tried to leave?
You came back to me,
and your curse came with you.
What do you think's
going to happen this time?
Set me free, and all this ends.
[Owen] I have a better idea.
Let's just finish this
once and for all.
[Catherine, distorted]
You can't kill me, Owen.
You know...
you might be right.
[Catherine] Owen.
[Catherine] Owen, stop!
[Owen] Iris might not want to see me,
but there's one thing
that I know for certain
is I'm gonna burn this place
to the ground.
And there'll be nothing left
for anyone to have to look after.
Owen, please, I'm your wife! Please!
You are not my wife.
[Catherine sobs] No, no, no!
You abandoned our daughter!
You weren't there as
she watched me rot with sickness!
[roars]
You. You're the monster, not me!
[roaring]
[light bulb shatters]
- [Owen panting]
- [lighter clicking]
[discordant music]
[Owen] No, no!
[Owen screaming]
[♪]
[low, sinister music]
[ticking]
[Owen] Iris.
[♪]
[Iris] Katie?
[Owen] Understand, witch.
[faint, indistinct whispering]
Burn it down. Kill her.
[whispering continues]
Katie?
Katie, you down here?
You don't belong here!
[Iris panting]
Run away, little girl.
[Iris] Where are you going?
Dad, where are you going?
- Stop! You can't go in there.
- You were never up to this. Ever!
She can sense your fear.
[Iris]
Dad, what's happening with your face?
Dad!
Stop. Stop. You're hurting yourself.
Stop.
[frenetic music]
- Stop it!
- [Owen grunting]
[♪]
What did you do to him?
[choking]
[gasping, choking]
[gasping]
[wheezing]
[Katie] Iris?
- Oh, my God.
- [Iris choking]
[♪]
[panting]
It's off. It's okay. You're okay.
[Iris panting]
[Iris] This was definitely it.
This was definitely his office.
Doesn't make any sense.
[Katie] Are you sure
that's the solicitor on the left?
Yeah, that's him.
[Katie] There's not even
a phone number.
Just the useless address
we've already been to.
It's like he knew.
He had to find some sucker
to put their name on the line,
and then he'd just disappear.
We're gonna take the money from Neil
and get the hell out of here.
It's happening just like
your dad said.
We used the witch, and now the dream.
- It's only gonna get worse.
- It was a nightmare.
Mate, you were being strangled
on the bathroom floor.
What are you doing, Iris?
You're acting like
you don't wanna leave this place.
Well, if I can't get
anything out of it,
then no, I don't.
This is all I have right now.
And then just think
about the amount of people
that would kill
to have something like this!
[shouting] Can you hear yourself?
This isn't something you can control!
Don't you understand?
It's her. She's in your head.
You should be scared.
You know what I am truly scared of?
Going back to my ordinary life,
a life where I don't have anything.
Maybe you don't want me to have this
because-- because we're good, yeah?
As long as I'm the screw-up
and you get to just take care of me.
But as soon as I have
something for myself,
you just wanna take it away.
You're a crutch.
What are you doing?
Yeah, yeah. Just walk out, then.
[door opens]
[door slams]
[ominous music]
[Katie] Friedland.
[thudding]
[wings fluttering]
[eerie music]
[♪]
What are you looking for, Otto?
You tried to get out, didn't you?
You know who I wanna see.
[Baghead shrieks]
[Owen panting]
[Owen] You can't be here.
- How did you find me?
- I own your pub.
No, that's not possible.
It's not possible.
I burned this place to the ground.
You were her keeper for years.
What is she?
I don't know.
I did not question
who she was or how she came to be.
That's it?
- That's all you've got for me?
- I didn't want you involved.
I didn't leave a will.
This wouldn't be happening
if you'd stayed away--
Maybe I would've stayed away
if you'd actually spoken to me!
And have you and your mother
pulled in too? No!
I tried to see you once, Iris,
a long time ago.
But as soon as I left this place...
horrible things followed me.
Freak accidents, sickness...
death.
Mom?
I didn't know what was gonna happen,
I swear.
I swear, I swear.
I came back here to protect you.
I just want to know,
how do I control her?
'Cause I'm-- I'm still the guardian.
She has to listen to me.
Until she gets inside your head.
And then the question is
who's listening to who.
- I was the same.
- We're not the same.
Yet here you are...
talking to me.
She's gotten to you, I can tell.
No, no.
I'm gonna sell this place and be gone
before anything like that
happens to me.
[Owen] As long as your name is
on the deed, you can't escape her.
You can't control her.
You can't kill her.
All you can do is not use her.
2,000 for two minutes?
You're a hypocrite!
[Owen] You're right.
And I took that mistake to the grave.
[timer ringing]
[distorted] Foolish girl.
Did you think I would be
proud of you?
Have you ever stopped to think
that maybe, just maybe,
she's not your curse?
That maybe...
you're hers.
There's some wisdom
that only suffering can bring.
I've had plenty of suffering.
[♪]
[gasps]
No! No!
[grunts]
I just wanted to say goodbye,
if only for a moment.
I failed you.
I failed you
and everyone I have ever loved.
Forgive me, Iris.
Forgive me.
But don't bring me back.
[groans]
[sombre music]
[Iris sobs]
Iris, I know you're upset,
but I followed the address
to the house of the old owner.
I think he may have some answers
for getting us out of this.
Can't believe I'm saying this,
but it might be worth
bringing him back.
I'm on my way to the pub now.
Call me back. Please.
[tense music]
[breathing heavily]
[sniffles]
She's your responsibility now.
And it's for life.
[♪]
You're a prisoner as soon as
you signed your name on that deed.
[♪]
You can't escape this place now.
Wherever you go...
[Iris screams]
...she will haunt you...
- until you come back.
- [Iris sobbing]
And we all come back.
We are the cursed ones.
[♪]
[Katie] Iris?
Iris!
Iris?
[unsettling music]
[cuckoo clock chiming]
[♪]
[hushed] Iris?
[light switch clicking]
[♪]
[disquieting music]
Iris, what have you done?
[Baghead growling]
[Katie gasping, panting]
[Baghead snarls]
[Baghead] Wait.
Are you Otto Vogler?
Why did you bring me back?
Can you-- can you help me find
the man in charge
so we can get out of this?
I-- I-- I know you were
looking for him.
There is no way out.
The man you dealt with is irrelevant.
Your fate was sealed 400 years ago
when an ancient brotherhood
discovered a woman
who could conjure the dead.
The brotherhood tried
to abuse her power.
But when she refused,
they branded her a witch
and burned her at the stake.
But death could not hold her.
Rising from the dead,
her vengeance was ruthless.
Disease spread among livestock.
Crops shrivelled, and the plague
spread among the people.
To stop her, the brotherhood
performed a dark ritual
and imprisoned her
in this underground tomb,
leaving her alone
and almost forgotten.
Centuries later,
the descendants of the brotherhood
opened her tomb
to abuse her power once again.
The more they used her,
the more power she gained
over the brotherhood,
who fell to sickness and death.
Now, there is only one guardian
to stand between her
and the outside world.
The one who signs the deed
inherits the curse
and must prevent her
from releasing her revenge.
But this-- this is a mistake.
We-- we shouldn't be here.
My friend never meant
to come to this place.
She inherited it.
Are you not the gatekeeper?
- I'm sorry.
- Sorry for what?
[Otto] There are no answers
for you here.
There is only pain.
[Katie screams]
[phone buzzing]
[buzzing continues]
- [Katie on phone] Iris.
- Katie?
Listen here, please.
[panting] Be quick. Just help me!
- Where are you?
- The basement. She's here.
- Help me!
- Shit.
[intense music]
Katie? Katie!
[Katie] Iris!
Iris!
Katie.
[Katie] Iris!
[Owen] Stay away from the hole.
[♪]
[Katie] In here!
Iris!
Katie?
[Katie] Iris, come on!
Katie!
[Katie] Iris!
- Katie? Keep talking.
- [Katie] Wait, I'm in here.
Iris!
- Over here!
- Katie.
Iris. Iris, oh, my God!
- Are you all right?
- Yeah, yeah, I'm fine. Are you?
- We have to go.
- You have to get me out of here.
- What if she comes back?
- It's okay. Just keep moving.
[clattering]
[♪]
[Katie] What is it, Iris?
Let's get out of here!
[sinister music]
No!
No, no, no, no.
[sobbing]
I'm going to kill you.
[distorted] So many people have tried.
Your father screamed like a child.
[Owen screaming]
[♪]
[Baghead growling]
[snarling]
[Iris panting]
[♪]
[Iris groans, coughs]
[Baghead roars]
[Iris grunts]
[Baghead growls]
[eerie music]
She was trying to save me.
[sniffles]
That's all she's ever done.
[liquid pouring]
Here.
They'll calm you down.
[sniffles]
So what do you wanna do now?
[sombre music]
My dad said...
he died...
knowing that
he'd failed everyone he loved.
And I hated him for it.
And I've just done the same.
Done the same thing.
No, this-- this ends with me.
Now.
We seal it forever.
No one will use her again.
She'll be powerless.
[tense music]
I can help you.
[Iris] Thanks.
You really shouldn't thank me.
Death seems to follow
everyone around me.
[faint, indistinct whispers]
[sighs]
- You all right?
- Yeah, I'm--
- You're still recovering.
- I'm fine.
- You should go rest.
I can do this.
Come on.
Sleep will help.
[rain pattering]
[clock ticking]
[cuckoo clock chiming]
They'll calm you down.
[ominous music]
[sighs]
[♪]
[Neil] You can trust me.
I'll be different from the others.
They didn't appreciate what they had.
Iris never wanted this place,
but I do.
It should've been me to begin with.
I can keep you safe.
All I want is to see Sarah
whenever I choose.
- [Baghead growling]
- No straps.
No timer.
Just us.
Can you do that?
- [growling]
- Here.
See? It's my name on the deed now.
I'm the guardian.
[raspy breathing]
I see.
[Baghead growls]
- [Sarah pants] I-- I remember now.
- [Neil] Sarah?
I remember what happened that night.
We had a fight over dinner,
didn't we?
I-- I told you I needed more space,
some time to think, and...
you were so calm.
You were upset.
I just wanted you to calm down.
No. My head was spinning.
- What did you give me?
- Just wine.
You always get so confused
when you drink.
Tell me the truth.
Tell me what happened, Neil!
It was just something
to calm you down.
It was to make you sleep
until we could talk.
How was I to know
you'd run for the car?
I mean, I wanted us
to spend our lives together,
and you were just gonna
walk out on that.
You were gonna abandon me
just like her!
Just like Mother!
But I can forgive you.
It was a comfort to know
there wasn't someone else.
It gave me hope for our son.
I was going to leave you
because I was scared.
Of you.
Of raising my child in that home.
I can't-- I mean, how-- how was I--
I couldn't have known, and--
Neil, we can still be together.
You know, it'll be--
it'll be like he's here too.
We can still be a family.
But not if she's the keeper.
[Neil] I don't understand.
We can't be a family if she's alive.
I'm not a murderer.
But you did kill me.
[distorted] You killed us.
You owe us.
They--
And what do you think she's
going to say when she finds out?
She won't. She won't know.
She already does.
Iris!
[intense music]
Let me go!
Sorry, but I can't lose her.
- Not again.
- That's not Sarah.
- You need to move on.
- I don't want to do that!
- [Iris grunts]
- [Neil shouts]
[both grunting]
[Iris panting]
[♪]
- [Neil] Iris!
- [pounding on door]
Iris!
[wood cracks]
[panting]
[♪]
- [Iris yelps]
- I can't let you bury her, Iris.
I'll remove my name.
I'll sign the pub over. Neil, stop.
- That's all I wanted.
- Please, stop.
But I don't think it's that simple,
is it?
- Stop, please!
- See, while you're still alive,
the pub is still yours,
isn't that right?
Let go of me.
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
[choking]
[Neil grunts]
Fuck you!
[Iris whimpers]
Please! [panting]
Please.
[screaming]
[thud]
[panting]
I tried to tell you.
Death follows me.
[ominous music]
[low growling]
I've done what you asked.
Now bring her back so
she can put my name on the deed.
[Baghead growls]
[♪]
[roaring]
I didn't want this to happen.
You have to believe me.
- You killed me.
- [Neil] I didn't have a choice.
- You're insane.
- I'm insane?
Imagine having this power
and not using it! That's insane!
Now let's make this right.
Tell me how I get my name
on the deed.
[distorted] I should thank you.
My guardian is dead.
And you brought her back.
Do you not understand?
My name is still on the deed.
I am still her master.
And now...
she...
is me.
- [light bulb shatters]
- Iris?
[Sarah] I was going to leave you
because I was scared.
- [Regina] I never wanted to be a mother.
- [Sarah] My head was spinning.
[Regina] I couldn't stand
the sight of you.
Every day was a little death.
You killed us.
[Neil screaming]
[Regina laughing]
- [Neil] No. No, no, no!
- Yes, sweet boy.
- [bones crack]
- [screaming]
[laughing]
[screaming]
[discordant music]
[Neil panting] Sarah. Sarah. Sarah.
- [Sarah] Hmm...
- Help me. Help me!
- Sweetheart.
- [whimpers] Help me.
Oh, sweetheart, don't worry.
Don't worry. I'll help you.
- Thank you. Thank you.
- Here.
- Thank you--
- [Sarah grunting]
[♪]
No. No, no.
[whimpering, panting]
[Owen] But she's always
the one pulling the strings.
[Neil] I need to see my wife.
[solicitor] May I ask what's
prompted this change of heart?
[Iris] I want a little time
in my dad's old place.
It's 4,000!
I just want a chance to say goodbye.
[Katie] You're acting like
you don't want to leave this place.
[Iris] We know what
we're dealing with.
[Katie] The more you use her,
the more control she has.
[Iris] She has to listen to me!
[Owen] Until she gets
inside your head.
[Neil] Next time,
we won't make mistakes.
[Sarah] We can still be together.
But not if she's the keeper.
This isn't something you can control!
- [grunts]
- [screaming]
- [Neil, wheezing] Iris!
- Goodbye, Neil.
[thud]
[exhales]
[♪]
[ominous music]